So we have this transaction response.
我们已经有了这个 `transactionResponse`
And we probably want our front end to give the user some indication,
我们还希望我们的前端能尽可能多的给用户一些指示
hey, the transaction went through.
比如 “嘿，交易已经通过”
So what we want to do is we want to listen to the blockchain for this to finish.
所以我们要做的就是监听区块链完成交易
So we can either listen for the TX to be mined.
所以我们要“监听交易的挖掘”
("listen for the tx to be mined")
Or we can listen for an event.
或者我们可以“监听一个事件”
("listen for an event")
We haven't learned about events yet. But we will.
我们还没有了解过关于“事件”("event")的内容，但之后会的
("<- we haven't learned about yet")
So for now, since we haven't learned about events yet, we're just going to listen for the TX to be mined.
所以现在，由于我们还没有学过“事件”，我们就选择监听交易的挖掘
Or to listen for the transaction to be mined, we're actually going to create a new function
为了监听交易的挖掘，我们需要创建一个新的函数
called function, listen, or transaction mine
名为 `function listenForTransactionMine()
in this is going to take as input a transaction response, and a provider.
它接收的输入是 `(transactionResponse, provider)`
Now you'll notice this isn't an async function.
你应该会注意到，这并不是一个 async 函数
For this section. This is intentional,
在本节中，这是刻意为之的
we don't want this to be an async function. And you'll see why in a second.
我们不希望它是一个 async 函数，你马上就会明白这是为什么
We're going to be using JavaScript promise JavaScript async functionality to its massive advantage.
我们将充分运用 JavaScript 的 "Promise" 和异步功能的优势
And this is why JavaScript actually works so well on the front end
这也是为什么 JavaScript 在前端中能够工作得如此出色
is because of how it's asynchronous.
就是因为它是异步的
So we're going to create this function listen for transaction to be mined,
所以我们要创建这个函数来监听交易的挖掘
we're going to await in our fund function.
我们要在 "fund" 函数中使用 await 关键字
And we're going to have this return a promise.
并将其返回一个 "Promise" 对象
Let's go ahead, and let's learn how to build this.
让我们继续，来学习一下如何构建它们
So we're gonna say console dot log, string interpolation, we'll say mining.
首先是 `console.log(``)`，字符串插值  `Mining ${}`
And then in here, we'll say transaction, response dot hash.
接着这里是 ``
All of our transaction response objects have a hash,
所有的 `transactionResponse` 对象都有一个 "hash"
which just represent that hash.
它表示的就是这个对象的“哈希值”("hash")
And we'll do a couple of data dot,
再来写几个句号 `...`
we'll put in our console here, we're waiting for the transaction to be mined,
我们把 console 放在这里，等待交易被挖掘出来
then what we're going to do is we're going to return a new promise.
接着我们要做的是 `return new Promise`
And the reason we're going to return a promise is because we need to create a listener for the blockchain.
我们要返回 "Promise" 的原因是，我们需要“创建一个用于区块链的监听器”
("create a listener for the blockchain")
We want to listen for this event to happen. But we want to tell JavaScript,
我们要监听这个事件的发生，但我们还想告诉 JavaScript
hey, wait for this thing to finish looking, wait for this thing to finish looking.
嘿，先等这个任务完成，先等这个任务完成
Now here's where this gets a little bit tricky.
到了这里就有点麻烦了
In our fund function. After we create the transaction,
在我们的 "fund" 函数中，在我们创建完这个交易之后
we basically want to tell JavaScript
我们想要告诉 JavaScript
Hey, wait for this TX to finish.
“嘿，等待这个交易完成”
("hey, wait for this TX to finish")
So our code is going to look as simple as
所以我们的代码看起来很简单，就像这样
await listen for transaction mine. And we're going to pass it the trans action response and our provider.
`await listenForTransactionMine()`，然后我们传入 `(transactionResponse)` 和 `provider`
So we're saying hey, listen for this transaction finish.
所以我们就是在说 “嘿，监听这个交易完成”
And we're using this await keyword,
并且我们正在使用 await 关键字
because again, the await keyword says
因为，再次强调，await 关键字就是在说
okay, we're gonna stop right here. We're gonna stop until this function is completely done.
OK 我们暂时停在这里，我们停在这一直到这个函数完全运行完毕
Now in this listen for transaction in mind,
现在，在这个 "listenForTransactionMine" 的内部
we have to define how we're actually going to listen for this.
我们需要定义一下到底该怎么进行监听
So we're going to say listen for this transaction to finish.
所以我们要做的就是 “监听这个交易完成”
("listen for this transaction finish")
Ethers actually comes with a way for us to listen for transactions and listen for events,
ethers 其实为我们提供了一种监听交易和事件的方法
which again, we haven't learned About, but don't worry about that yet.
但是，我们还没学过那些，不过也不用担心那些
So we can go to the ethers docs. And we can look up once. Contract dot once.
我们可以前往 "ethers docs"，然后检索 "once", "contract.once"
There's a whole bunch of listeners that we can use
这里有一大堆“监听器”("listener")可以使用
to listen for events and listen for different things to happen,
它们用来监听事件以及各种不同事情的发生
we can do this thing called provider dot once
我们可以使用这个名为 "provider.once" 的方法
where we listen for some event.
来监听某个事件
And once that event fires, we call some other function that we've defined.
一旦该事件被触发，我们就调用某个我们定义好的函数
Now, we haven't talked about events yet.
我们还没有谈论过关于“事件”("event")的内容
And again, don't worry about this quite yet.
但再次提醒，完全都不用担心这个
One of the events that we can wait for is we can just wait for the transaction receipt to finish, right,
其中一个我们可以等待的事件就是，等待“交易回执”("transaction receipt")的完成，对吧？
because once we get a transaction receipt,
因为一旦我们获取到了交易回执
that means that the transaction has actually finished going through.
就意味着交易实际上已经完成了
So we're going to use this provider dot once syntax
所以我们就要使用这个 "provider.once" 语法
to wait for the transaction receipt, which is going to be our event,
来等待交易回执，也就是我们的事件
which isn't really an event, but don't worry about that yet.
它并不是一个真正的事件，但暂时不用管这个
And then we're going to call some listener function that we defined,
然后我们要调用某个我们定义的监听器函数
you can also do provider.on,
你也可以使用 "provider.on"
which will trigger anytime your event fires
它会在你的事件每次触发时都被触发
provider once just triggers one time,
而 "provider.once" 只会触发一次
we only care about this transaction going through one time.
我们只关心这个交易是否通过了，一次
So we're passing our provider object. So we're gonna say
我们传入了我们的 "provider" 对象，所以我们可以说
provider dot once our event which is just going to be transaction response, hash,
`provider.once()`，其中是我们的事件，也就是 `transactionResponse.hash`
provided on transaction response dot hash.
完整的就是 `provider.once(transactionResponse.hash)`
So once we get this hash,
所以，一旦我们获取到了这个 "hash"
which will pretty much get right away, we're going to call our listener function.
几乎就是立刻，我们就会调用我们的 `listener` 函数
Now we can create a function listener like this,
现在我们可以创建一个 `function listener()` 就像这样
and then just pass listener in here.
并把 `listener` 直接传入这里
But we're going to do an anonymous function here, because that's
但我们这里打算用一个匿名函数
typically what we see as the syntax for these
因为这才是我们通常会看到的语法
loops. And so far, we're doing provider dot once
哎呀，抱歉，我们还在说 "provider.once" 呢
to do this anonymous function, we're going to do just two little parentheses here. And this arrow notation.
为了创建这个匿名函数，我们只需要在这里加上两个小括号，还有一个箭头符号
So this by itself represents an anonymous function.
这就表示了一个匿名函数
So we're saying, hey, there's some function, it doesn't take any parameters, and it doesn't have any code,
就相当于在说“嘿，这里有个函数，它不接收任何参数，也没有任何代码”
this arrow function, this whole thing is saying this is an anonymous function.
这个箭头函数，整个就是在说，这是一个匿名函数
So we're saying provided at once transaction hash happens,
所以我们说的就是 "provider.once(transactionResponse.hash)" 发生了
here's the function that you want to execute.
而这里是你想要启动的函数
It doesn't do anything right now.
但它现在还并没有做任何事情
But let's have a do something.
不过让我们还是做点什么吧
So once this transaction dot response finishes,
所以一旦这个 "transactionResponse" 完成了
we're going to take a trans transaction received as an input parameter,
我们就要接收一个 `transactionReceipt` 作为输入参数
or our our callback function, or our listener function.
可以说是我们的“回调函数”("callback function") 或者“监听器函数”("listener function")
And all we're going to do is we're gonna say console dot log, completed with a little string interpolation,
我们要做的就是 `console.log(`Completed with ${}`)` 一个字符串插值
transaction receipt, that confirmations, confirmations,
`transactionReceipt.confirmations`
and then completed with transaction receipt, confirmations, confirmations.
接着是 `console.log(`Completed with $ confirmations`)`
So once this provider dot once sees that there's a transaction hash,
所以一旦 "provider.once" 看到了一个交易哈希
it's going to give as an input rammer to our listener function, the transaction receipt,
它就会给监听器函数输入一个参数 "transactionReceipt"
kind of that same syntax that we've been seeing this whole time,
类似的语法我们会一直见到
once a transaction response finishes, we get the transaction receipt,
一旦 "transactionResponse" 完成，就获取 "transactionReceipt"
and we can do stuff with it.
我们可以以此来进行操作
And we see how many block confirmations it has.
我们可以看看有多少区块已经确认了
For us, this pretty much should always be one.
对我们来说，基本上应该始终为 1
Now if we save this, go back to our front end, and we hit fund,
现在，如果我们保存一下，然后回到我们的前端，并点击 "Fund"
it's going to work, we're going to give the user some indication that it worked, which is great.
它会正常工作，并且我们会给用户一些指示，说明它确实如此，非常好
But it's not really going to work the way that we want it to work.
但这还不是我们希望它工作的方式
We have this console dot log done right after we do the await, listen for transaction mine,
我们在运行完 "await listenForTransactionMine" 之后添加这个 `console.log("Done!")`
and we come back and we hit fund, we hit confirm,
接着我们回来并点击 "Fund" 点击“确认”("Confirm")
it actually doesn't go in the order that we want it to go,
它实际上并没有按照我们想要的顺序进行操作
it goes mining this thing that it says Done.
它先说了“挖掘”("Mining")这个东西，然后它说了“完成”("Done!")
And then it says completed with one trip confirmation
接着它说“完成了 1 次确认”("Completed with 1 confirmations")
what what's going on here,
这里发生了什么？
we should write completed before we write done,
我们应该把 "Completed" 写在 "Done!" 的前面
because that's the order that we have this in.
因为这才是我们想要的顺序
But it looks like it's words, it's going out of order. What what's going on here,
但看起来这些单词的顺序错乱了，这里到底发生了什么？
what's going to happen is when we call listen for transaction mine,
当我们调用 "listenForTransactionMine" 时
or listen for transaction, mine function is going to kick off,
或者说 "listenForTransactionMine" 启动时
but it's going to kick off provided on once as its own process.
它还会以自己的进程启动 `provider.once`
So await listen for transaction, mine will kick off the listener,
所以 "await listenForTransactionMine" 会启动监听器
but it doesn't wait for this listener to find the transaction response.
但却不会等待监听器查找 "transactionResponse"
So this function will actually finish before provider dot once finishes.
所以这个函数在 "provider.once" 完成之前就结束了
So after it kicks off the listener,
所以，启动完监听器之后
it'll run to the next line of our code, which is console dot log and done.
它就会运行我们的下一行代码，也就是 "console.log("Done!")"
Our front end we'll go
我们的前端就会说
oh, oh, you kicked off a listener earlier.
哦，你早些时候启动了一个监听器
Let me go back down and let me recheck to see if it's finished.
让我回去重新检查一下，看看它完成了没有
And if it has finished, I'll go do what it told me to do.
如果它已经完成了，我就继续做它让我做的事
And this is where what's known as the event loop kicks in.
这就是所谓的“事件循环”("event loop")要发挥作用的地方了
We don't actually wait for this provider that wants to finish,
我们实际上并不会等待这个应该完成的 "provider"
we add this provided at once onto this queue called the event loop.
而是把它添加到一个被称为“事件循环”的队列中
And our front end is going to periodically check back to it to see if it's finished.
前端会定期检查该队列以查看它是否已经完成
So we want to adjust our code. So we wait for the listener to finish listening,
所以我们需要调整代码，等待监听器完成监听
which is where we're going to get into promises here.
这就是我们要深入探讨 "Promise" 的地方了
So what we want to do is we want to adjust this function to now return a promise.
所以我们要调整这个函数，让它现在返回一个 "Promise"
And we're going to use this syntax a couple of times in the future.
在未来，我们会经常用到这种语法
So what we're going to do is we're going to say
所以我们要做的就是告诉它
hey, we want to wait for the listener To finish listening,
嘿，我们要等待监听器完成监听
we're going to wrap this whole thing into a promise.
我们将把这一整个东西包装成一个 "Promise"
And we're going to say return, new promise.
所以我们要写 `return new Promise()`
And a promise takes a function itself as an input parameter.
"Promise" 接收一个函数作为它的参数
So again, we'll use kind of this anonymous function notation.
所以，我们又一次要使用到这种匿名函数表示
And it will take two input parameters resolve and reject.
而它接收两个输入参数 `resolve` 以及 `reject`
So resolve says,
"resolve" (“解析”)说的就是
hey, if this promise works correctly, call this resolve function.
嘿，如果这个 "Promise" 工作正常，就调用这个 "resolve" 函数
And for us, this promise is going to be done when the listener finishes listening.
对我们来说，这个 "Promise" 将在监听器完成监听的时候执行
And then we would reject if there was some type of timeout,
而在某种类型的超时出现时，我们就会选择“拒绝”("reject")
we're not going to write the reject function.
我们并不会编写 "reject" 函数
But in the future, if you were to do this for production,
但在将来，如果你要将其应用到产品上
you'd add some timeout as the reject parameter.
就要将超时时间作为 "reject" 的参数
Basically, you're saying, hey, once the listener finishes listening, we're going to resolve
基本上就是，嘿，一旦监听器完成监听，我们就要运行 "resolve"
and if it takes too long, we're gonna say ask for you, you took too long,
而如果时间过长，我们就会提示你，你花费的时间太长了
and instead of closing it off, here,
并不是在这里结束
we're going to close it off around this provider thing.
而是要把这个 "provider" 包起来再结束
So we're gonna say return new promise, resolve, reject.
所以就是 `return new Promise((resolve, reject))`
And only once this transaction gets fired, are we going to resolve this promise,
并且只有在 "transactionResponse" 触发时，我们才 `resolve()`(“解析”)这个 Promise
like so.
就像这样
So what is happening here,
所以，这里发生了些什么呢？
so we're going to put the resolve inside of this provider at once.
我们把 "resolve()" 放在了 "provider.once" 的内部
So we're saying, once this transaction hash is found, then we're going to call this function,
也就是说，一旦这个交易的哈希值被找到，我们就调用这个函数
we're gonna say console dot log, and then we're going to resolve
我们会输出 "console.log()" 接着执行 "resolve()"
so this promise only returns once a resolve or reject is called.
因此，这个 "Promise" 只有在 "resolve" 或 "reject" 被调用后才会返回
And we're telling it
而我们告诉它
only resolve only finish this function once. Transaction response dot hash is found,
"resolve()" 这个函数，只有在 "once(transactionResponse.hash)" 被找到时才会完成
because it's going to be inside of these little squiggly parentheses for provider dot once,
因为它位于 "provider.once" 的小波浪线内部
the promise right now only resolves after it's fired. It's event here.
现在 "Promise" 只有在这个事件被触发之后才会被解析
If this was really confusing,
如果这里真的很令你感到困惑的话
just copy paste this and move on,
直接复制粘贴，然后继续前进
we're getting a little bit deeper into front end stuff here.
我们还会更深入地探讨前端相关的内容
So hopefully, this was clear,
希望这些已经讲清楚了
if not definitely jump in to the GitHub discussions to start asking about this stuff.
如果没有的话，请一定要前往 GitHub 的讨论区询问这部分的相关内容
But now that we've updated this,
总之，现在我们已经更新好了这个
we can come back to our front end, we can hit the fund button.
我们可以回到前端，点击 "Fund" 按钮
And hopefully this time, everything will go in order.
希望这一次，一切都能如期运行
We'll hit confirm, we see mining completed, and then we see done.
点击“确认”("Confirm")，可以看到 "Mining", "Completed" 然后我们才看到 "Done!"
And the reason for this is because again, our await keyword is now waiting, it says
这一切的原因是，我们的 await 关键字正在等待，它在说
oh, you're returning a promise, I need to await I need to wait for it to resolve or reject.
哦！你返回了一个 "Promise"，我需要等待它被解析或者被拒绝
And we only resolve the promise once our provider finds this transaction hash and this transaction receipt,
并且，只有 "provider" 找到了这个交易的哈希值和回执后，我们才解析 "Promise"
this is this listen for transaction mine.
这就是 "listenForTransactionMine"
In future sections, all of this is going to be abstracted away for us.
在未来的章节中，这些都会被抽象化处理
So life is going to be much easier,
所以会变得更简单一些
but it is important to understand what's actually going on here.
但理解它实际上是怎么运作的仍然非常重要
Awesome. So now we're giving the front end some indication of what's going on.
太棒了，现在我们就给了前端一些指示，表明了现在正在发生写什么
Our fun function is done
我们的 "fund" 函数已经完成了
well, no, not really. Why not?
好吧，其实并没有，为什么呢？
Well, because right now we're hard coding the eath amount to 0.1.
因为现在，我们还在把 "ethAmount" 硬编码为 0.1
And on the front end, we probably don't want to hard code it,
在前端中，我们并不希望它是被硬编码的
we probably want to allow users to fund as much or as little as they want.
我们希望用户可以自由的选择它们能够资助的金额
So we actually need to change this from just a button to a input form.
所以我们需要把这个按钮修改为一个“输入表单”("input form")
So to do this, we're gonna go back over into our HTML.
要处理这一点，我们需要回到我们的 HTML
So we'll go back to index dot HTML.
所以我们回到我们的 "index.html"
And we're going to change this fun section here, we're going to add some form information.
我们要修改一下这里的 "fund" 部分，添加一些表单信息
So we're going to keep this button as it is, or we're going to add like a little text box
我们要保持这个按钮不变，但要添加一个小的文本框
to input as much eath as they want.
用于输入他们想输入的以太币金额
So I'm going to create a label, we're gonna say it's for, it's going to be fund
所以我要创建一个 `
and this label we're gonna say, is eath amount,
这个 "label" 名字是 "ETH Amount"
and then we're gonna close label,
然后我们要关闭标签 ""
this is basically just going to create a label. And if we go back to our front end, we
now just have this Etham out label that isn't labeling
anything. Now we're going to create an input, and we're going
to give it an ID of eath amount. And we're going to give it a
placeholder
of 0.1. And then we're gonna close the input. So now if we
flip to our front end, we have eath amount, labeling this
little text box with a placeholder of 0.1. And we can
add stuff in here, you know, blah, blah, whatever. And one
more thing, if you have some tags, but you don't put anything
in between them, you can actually shorten it by just
putting the little closing thing at the back of it like this. So
if you don't have anything between your tags, you can just
close them like this, these two are equivalent, boom, boom,
boom, boom, those are the same thing. Great. When we called
fund right now we're calling fund and we're not passing any
parameters. Let's update our fund to no longer be hardcoding
eath amount in here, and we'll have and we'll have our fund
function populated by whatever we put in this eath amount input
box in our fund function, instead of saying const eath
amount equals 0.1. We'll grab it from this eath amount ID and
we'll say document dot get element by ID eath amount, dot
value. So we're going to grab whatever value In this input box
here, now, in our index.js, we have console dot log funding
with eath amount, if in our front end, we do 1.7. And we hit
fund, we now see in our console dot log, it says funding with
1.7. And we'll get 1.7. And our little fun section confirm, it
will mine it, it'll complete it, and then say, done. Awesome. So
now we've added a little text box here. So people can fund as
much or as little as they want. Perfect, this whole thing can
kind of be considered a form. There's also a form tag, but
we're going to just use this for now.